Inventory of the Christopher Newport College Records 1959-1977
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Christopher Newport College Records 1959-1977
Special Collections Research Center
00/01/UA 87
1.20
Series 1: Acc. 1984.069: This series contains Budgets, from 1963-1976, and capital outlay requests from 1966-1972, that were submitted to the Virginia State Legislature. They include appropriations requests and justifications.
College of William and Mary. Christopher Newport College arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center from Various transfers and gifts. on 09/26/1984.
Accruals
Future accruals are not expected.
Custodial History
The provenance of the material that was removed from the University Archives Publications Collection related to the Norfolk Division is not documented.
Historical Note
The General Assembly of Virginia established Christopher Newport College as a non-residential branch college of The College of William and Mary in 1960. Christopher Newport College was authorized by the Board of Visitors of The College of William and Mary to offer a lower-level undergraduate liberal arts curriculum. In 1969, the Board of Visitors received approval from the General Assembly to add upper-level bachelor's programs and award Bachelor of Arts and Bachelor of Science Degrees. Christopher Newport College was established as a four-year baccalaureate institution independent of The College of William and Mary in 1976. CNC's first Board of Visitors was appointed by the Governor on July 1, 1977. In 1990, the General Assembly authorized CNC to offer degrees at the master's level. Christopher Newport College became Christopher Newport University July 1, 1992.
Scope and Contents
Series 1: Acc. 1984.069: This series contains Budgets, from 1963-1976, and capital outlay requests from 1966-1972, that were submitted to the Virginia State Legislature. They include appropriations requests and justifications.
Series 2: This series contains publications produced by Christopher Newport from 1959-1977. The inventory for this accession is available below in the finding aid/inventory section of this finding aid.
Additional Information
Physical Characteristics or Technical Requirements
Portions of this collection are stored offsite. Consult staff for assistance.
Related Materials
See also the University Archives Photograph Collection (UA 8), records of the Office of the President (UA 2), and other administrative records.
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Financial records; Publications
Topical Term:
Associated and Branch Campuses--Christopher Newport College; College of William and Mary--History--20th century.; Education, Higher--Virginia--History.; Newport News (Va.)--History.
Detailed Description of the Collection
  Series 1: Acc. 1984.069
- Acc. 1984.069, 1963-1976
  Series 1: Acc. 1984.069: This series contains Budgets, from 1963-1976, and capital outlay requests from 1966-1972, that were submitted to the Virginia State Legislature. They include appropriations requests and justifications. This accession is not yet fully described here.
  Series 2: Publications
- Publications, 1959-1977
  This series contains publications produced by Christopher Newport from 1959-1977.
  - (1)
    - Christopher Newport College, 1959-1977 (1)
    - Budget, 1964-1966 (1, 2)
    - Faculty, By-Laws, and Salaries, 1966 (1, 3)
    - Faculty Handbook, 1976 (1, 4)
    - Film Festival, 1968 (1, 5)
    - Financial Reports, 1973-1975 (1, 6)
    - Library, 1964-1966 (1, 7)
    - Registration, 1964-1966 (1, 8)
    - Self-Study, 1975 (1, 9)
    - Statement of Purposes and Programs, 1961 (1, 10)
    - Trident, 1964-1965 (1, 11)
  - (2)
    - Trident, 1965 (2, 1)
    - Trident, 1966 (2)
    - Trident, 1969 (2, 3)
    - Trident, 1970 (2, 4)
    - Trident, 1970 (2, 5)
    - Trident, 1971 (2, 6)
    - The Undertow, 1970 (2, 7)
    - Virginia's Boundaries, 1973 (2, 8)